Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials MC.230
New York University Archives
- Series VII. Lecture Presentation Support Images, 1863-1900, undated; 1 linear foot in 3 custom boxes.
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14805 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Blank Slide, undated; cuid14736 (Box 32, Folder 105)
  - Empty Slide, undated; cuid14745 (Box 32, Folder 114)
- Series VIII: Daguerreotypes, 1860, undated; 1.50 Linear Feet in 1 card box and 3 custom boxes.
  This series contains a daguerreotype portrait of NYU alumnus and writer Cornelias Mathews, 24 blank daguerreotype sheets, and a glass cover.
  - Circular Image -- Bonine and Iodine to Red Used, 14 November 1860; cuid14807 (Box 35)
  - Daguerreotype Glass Cover, undated; cuid14870 (Box 10)
  - 24 Blanks for Daguerreotypes, undated; cuid14806 (Box 15)
  - Cornelius Mathews Portrait, undated; cuid14808 (Box 36)
- Series IX. Document Reproductions and Memorial Images, 1843-1899; 3.25 Linear Feet in 2 custom boxes and 1 oversize flat box.
  This series includes images of the Henry Draper Memorial, possibly a portrait of Henry Draper in Civil War uniform, a portrait of John Johnson, an insect, and reproductions of images of unidentified documents.
  - Reproduction of a John Johnson Photograph, 1843; cuid14898 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Handwritten Notes Reproduction, circa 1850-1899; cuid14886 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Insect Image, circa 1850-1899; cuid14887 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Book Page Reproduction, circa 1850-1899; cuid14888 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Book Page Reproduction, circa 1850-1899; cuid14894 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Illustration of Superior Vena Cava and Human Head, circa 1850-1899; cuid14893 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Book Page Reproduction, circa 1850-1899; cuid14897 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Portraits of a Man (Possibly Henry Draper) in a Union Military Uniform, circa 1860s; cuid2007 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Book Page Reproduction -- "Chapter 7", circa 1890s; cuid14895 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Book Page Reproduction -- "Chapter 7", circa 1890s; cuid14896 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Henry Draper Memorial -- Spectra -- Canis Minoris, undated; cuid2080 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Henry Draper Memorial -- Spectra -- Canis Majoris, Cygni, Canis Minoris, Aurgae, Bootis, undated; cuid14564 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Portrait of a Woman, undated; cuid2006 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Portraits of a Woman, undated; cuid14631 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Train Station and Tracks Next to Polo Grounds and Grand Stand, undated; cuid14580 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Unknown Objects, undated; cuid1923 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - No Image, undated; cuid2039 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified, undated; cuid1940 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Series X. Original Storage Housing, 1915, undated; 3 Linear Feet in 4 custom boxes.
  This series contains boxes which had orginally held the lantern slides and glass plate negatives in this collection.
  - Wooden Lantern Slide Box, March 1915; cuid14867 (Box 27)
  - Wooden Lantern Slide Box, March 1915; cuid14868 (Box 28)
  - Wooden Lantern Slide Box, undated; cuid14869 (Box 29)
  - Wooden Cabinet for Glass Plate Negatives, undated; cuid14874 (Box 40)
    ID Number: 286. Description: containing spectral slides. Creator/Donor/Subject: Draper, Henry.